Guide to the Eugenia Flatow Papers 1940-2011 (bulk 1963-2005) MS 3175
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Waterfronts, Waterways, and Waterborne Transportation, 1943-2005 (bulk 1971-2005)
  - Subseries III.D. Published Materials, 1943-2001 (bulk 1971-1999)
    - River City (report), 1985 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 13)
    - New York City's Waterfront: A Plan for Development, 1986 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 14)
    - Wastes in Marine Environments, 1987 April (Offsite-box 24, Folder 15)
    - Grand Slam Victory for Conservation! CEE Scores Major Successes on 4 Fronts, 1987 September (Offsite-box 24, Folder 16)
    - America's Wetlands: Our Vital Link Between Land and Water, 1988 February (Offsite-box 24, Folder 17)
    - The Future of New York City's Waterfront, 1989 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 18)
    - The Greenhouse Effect: How It Can Change Our Lives, 1989 January/February (Offsite-box 24, Folder 19)
    - The Wasted Ocean, 1989 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 20)
    - A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park, 1990 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 21)
    - Records of New Jersey Birds, 1991 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 22)
    - Plans for the Waterfront (3 Folders), 1993 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 23-25)
      This file contains plans for the Queens, Bronx, and Manhattan waterfronts published by the New York City Department of City Planning.
    - The Public Trust Doctrine On Long Island: Public and Private Rights in Coastal Areas, 1994 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 26)
    - Reclaiming the Waterfront: A Planning Guide for Waterfront Municipalities, 1996 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 27)
    - Port Guide NY/NJ, 1996 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 28)
    - Investing in the Waterfront: New York City's Waterfront Revitalization Program, 1997 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 29)
    - A Culture of Mismanagement: Environmental Protection and Enforcement at the New York City Department of Environmental Protection, 1997 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 30)
    - Under Attack: New York's Kensico and West Branch Reservoirs Confront Intensified Development, 1999 February (Offsite-box 24, Folder 31)
    - The Rare Plant: Propagation Project, 2001 July (Offsite-box 24, Folder 32)
- Series IV. Organizational Records, 1961-2010 (bulk 1970s-1990s)
  Series IV contains materials related to Eugenia Flatow's leadership positions in various public and private organizations, committees, and task-forces dedicated to parks and open space development, environmental policy, and waterfront revitalization. She held many of these roles concurrently, and as a result the goals and projects of the documented organizations overlap.
  Series IV is organized in nine subseries:
  Subseries IV.A. The Parks Council, 1961-1992 (bulk 1974-1985)
  Subseries IV.B. Neighborhood Open Space Coalition / Friends of Gateway (NOSC/FoG), 1972-2001
  Subseries IV.C. Environmental Policy Forum (EPF), 1976-2002
  Subseries IV.D. Coalition for the Bight, 1977-2010 (bulk 1970s-1990s)
  Subseries IV.E. New York- New Jersey Harbor Estuary Program (HEP), 1980-2004
  Subseries IV.F. Manhattan Community Board #9, 1981-1992
  Subseries IV.G. Jamaica Bay Task Force (JBTF), 1981-2006
  Subseries IV.H. The City Club of New York, 1986-2008 (bulk 1991-2005)
  Subseries IV.I. New York City Soil and Water Conservation District (NYCSWCD), 1994-2007
  - Subseries IV.A. The Parks Council, 1961-1992 (bulk 1974-1985)
    The Parks Council was an independent organization dedicated to the creation, conservation, and enhancement of New York City's parks, open space, and waterfront for the use and enjoyment of the public. Subseries IV.A. contains correspondence, brochures, newsletters, reports, publications, and research files related to Eugenia Flatow's role as president. Materials in this series cover matters concerning the future of the urban environment, including park policy, open space development, and funding for recreational and educational programs. This subseries also contains records of the Committee on City Waterfront and Waterways, which worked to further the interests of waterborne service for both people and commerce and advocate greater access to the waterfront for the people of the City of New York.
    - 1989 Urban Conservation Corps/Work Study Program Evaluation (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture and Marine Employment, circa 1976 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2)
    - Andrew Fletcher, 1985 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3)
    - Breezy Point, 1963 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 4)
    - Brochures, circa 1983 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5)
    - Bronx, 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 6)
    - Bronx River, 1974-1983 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn (2 Folders), 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 8-9)
    - Canal Program (1973-1978), 1974 December (Offsite-box 25, Folder 10)
    - Central Park, 1964 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 11)
    - Clearwater, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 12)
    - Coastal Management (2 Folders), 1974-1985 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 13-14)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 15)
    - The Cousteau Society, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 16)
    - Creating Public Access to the Brooklyn Waterfront, 1990 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 17)
    - Department of Environmental Protection (DEP), 1972, 1975 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 18)
      This file contains guides to New York City's Air Pollution (circa 1975) and Noise Control (circa 1972) codes.
    - Endangered Natural Areas Symposium (program), 1978 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 19)
    - Environmental Ed, 1975 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 20)
    - Events, 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 21)
    - Fort Totten, circa 1988 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 22)
    - Gateway (2 Folders), 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 23-24)
    - A Greenway Plan for New York City, 1993 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 25)
    - Habitat, 1974-1991 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 26)
    - Hudson River Maritime, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 27)
    - Managing the Department of Parks and Recreation in a Period of Fiscal Stress, 1991 March (Offsite-box 25, Folder 28)
    - Manhattan (2 Folders), 1982-1985 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 29-30)
    - Marine Recreation Parks, 1973-1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 31)
    - McKeown and Franz, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 32)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 33)
    - The Municipal Art Society, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 34)
    - National Maritime Historical Society (NMHS), 1984 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 35)
    - New Jersey (3 Folders), 1981-1985 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1-3)
    - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (NYS-DEC), 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
    - North Manhattan Parks: A Study, circa 1980 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
    - Operation Sail, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6)
    - Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Subcommittee, 1974-1984 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 7)
    - Parks (3 Folders), 1961-1985 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 8-10)
      Contains brochures, correspondence, maps, pamphlets, and reports related to park policy and development.
    - Parks and Playgrounds, 1961-1964 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 11)
    - The Parks Council (Publications), 1974-1990 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 12)
    - Parks Council Newsletters (4 Folders), 1971-1985 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 13-16)
      In addition to The Parks Council Newsletter, these folders contain annual reports, brochures, correspondence, memorandums, and records related to the Council's annual meetings.
    - Parks Council, Borough Communities (2 Folders), 1974-1985, bulk 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 17-18)
      Contains documentation related to the development and evaluation of The Parks Council Work/Study program.
    - Photos, circa 1970-1980 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 19)
      This file contains photos of Ellis Island, Liberty Island, Liberty State Park, South Street Seaport, Battery Park, several Brooklyn neighborhoods, and other locations in New York City. The photographs are part of the New York Harbor Park proposal prepared by the Parks Council in October 1980.
    - The Port of New York and New Jersey (3 Folders), 1978-1985 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 20-22)
    - A Region at Risk (report), 1996 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 23)
    - Riverbank (2 Folders), 1979-1985 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Riverside Park, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 3)
    - Sea Grant (2 Folders), 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 4-5)
    - South Bronx Waterfront Action Task Force, 1974 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 6)
    - South Street (2 Folders), 1972-1985 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 7-8)
    - State Parks, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 9)
    - Sue Jackson, circa 1977 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 10)
    - Trees for New York City, 1977 May (Offsite-box 27, Folder 11)
    - Waterborne Transportation (2 Folders), 1975-1985 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 12-13)
    - Wateredges Project, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 14)
      Materials related to the development of the Wateredges Project. The project was sponsored by the New York City Bicentennial Corporation under a grant from the National Endowment of the Arts. The goal was to refocus community attention to the potential offered by the wateredges for educational, historical, cultural, and recreational use.
    - Waterfront Committee (3 Folders), 1974-1986 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 15-17)
    - Waterfront Management Board, 1974-1984 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 18)
    - Waterfront Management Plan Report, 1989 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 19)
    - Waterfront Slides, 1974 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 20)
    - Waterfront Study, 1974-1980 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 21)
    - Waterfront, 1974-1992 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 22)
    - West Side Highway (2 Folders), 1972-1985 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 23-24)
    - Westway (3 Folders), 1976-1986 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 25-27)
  - Subseries IV.B. Neighborhood Open Space Coalition / Friends of Gateway (NOSC/FoG), 1972-2001
    Established in 1980, the Neighborhood Open Space Coalition (NOSC) was developed to improve the quality of life for all New Yorkers by expanding and enhancing the city's parks and open spaces through research, planning, and advocacy. In 1992, Friends of Gateway (FoG), an advocacy and service organization, joined with NOSC to protect, improve and enhance public awareness of, and access to Gateway National Recreation Area. Subseries IV.B. contains correspondence, studies, agendas, financial documentation, minutes, memorandums, proposals, and reports mostly from the period before NOSC and FoG merged. However, there is also a considerable amount of material related to the Gateway National Recreation Area and the Gateway Citizens Committee.
    - Brooklyn Piers 1-6: A Framework for Discussion (report), 1986 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn Queens Greenway, 1990 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 2)
    - The Brooklyn/Queens Greenway: A Design Study, 1988 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 3)
    - The Brooklyn/Queens Greenway: A Feasibility Study, undated (Offsite-box 30, Folder 4)
    - Conserving Open Space, 1987-1992 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 5)
    - Festivals (2 Folders), 1994 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 6-7)
    - Filing, 1991-1994 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 8)
    - Friends of Gateway Ferry Service, 1996 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 9)
    - Fund Raising, 1992-1994 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 10)
    - Gateway (5 Folders of 6), 1972-1993 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 11-15)
      Contains agendas, brochures, correspondence, meeting minutes, memorandums, proposals, and reports related to the Gateway National Recreation Area and the Gateway Citizens Committee.
    - Gateway (1 Folder of 6). Oversize, 1972-1993 (Folder FF-1)
      File contains a map of the potential waterborne routes and embarcation points of the Gateway National Recreation Area.
    - Gateway Finances, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 16)
    - A Gateway to Gateway (report), 1977 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 17)
    - Gateway, Floyd Bennett Field, 1983 September (Offsite-box 30, Folder 18)
    - Gateway, General Management Plan, 1979 August (Offsite-box 30, Folder 19)
    - Gateway, Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 20)
    - Governor's Island, 1995 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 21)
    - Greenway Proposals, 1993-1996 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 22)
    - Info Pieces, undated (Offsite-box 30, Folder 23)
    - Manual for Community Participation in the New York City Budget Process, 1986 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 24)
    - New York City's Waterfront: A Plan for Development, 1986 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 25)
    - NOSC Administration, 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 26)
    - NOSC Budget, 1996-1998 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 27)
    - NOSC By-Laws, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 28)
    - NOSC Correspondence (2 Folders), 1984-2001, bulk 1996 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 29-30)
    - NOSC Correspondence, 1984-2001, bulk 1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    - NOSC Financial Statement, 1985 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - NOSC Fiscal (2 Folders), 2001 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3-4)
    - NOSC General Support Proposal, 1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
    - NOSC Minutes (3 Folders), circa 1986-1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6-8)
    - NOSC, Miscellaneous, 1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 9)
    - Open Space and the Future of New York, 1987 September (Offsite-box 31, Folder 10)
    - Open Space, South Bronx, 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 11)
    - The Open Space Imperative, 1987-1990 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 12)
    - Organization and Staffing Charts, Gateway National Recreation Area, 1993 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 13)
    - Port Imperial Ferry Bus System, 1990 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 14)
      Contains brochures, newsletters, and a pin that reads "Love to Ride that Ferry!"
    - Program Proposals and Project Reports, 1987-1995 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 15)
    - A Proposal to Construct a 116' Vessel to Establish a Ferry Service for Gateway National Park, 1978 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 16)
    - The Re-greening of Urban America, undated (Offsite-box 31, Folder 17)
    - Recreation and Open Space in New York City (2 Folders), 1995-1998 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 18-19)
      These New York City Department of City Planning reports provide the baseline information needed to assess patterns of regional open space and recreational opportunity in the Bronx, Brooklyn, Manhattan, Queens, and Staten Island.
    - Regional Plan (1 of 2), circa 1984-1990 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 20)
    - Regional Plan (2 of 2). Oversize, circa 1984-1990 (Folder OS-Large, Folder 1)
      File contains a map prepared by the Regional Plan Association to illustrate some of the opportunities to create a network of greenspaces and greenways in New York.
    - Reports to the Board from NOSC Finance Committee, 1986 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 21)
    - Rockaway Gateway Greenway (RGG), "ISTEA" Project (2 Folders), 1995-1998 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 22-23)
      Documentation related to the Rockaway Gateway Greenway – a planned twenty-mile bicycle/pedestrian system within the Gateway National Recreation Area. Materials include correspondence, meeting minutes, and a summary report of the project.
    - Toward the Creation of a New York City Open Space Task Force, 1982 April (Offsite-box 31, Folder 24)
    - Transportation Demonstration Program for Improving Access to Gateway National Recreation Area, 1977 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 25)
    - Urban Open Space -- An Investment That Pays (2 Folders), 1995-1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 26-27)
      This folder contains "Urban Open Space -- An Investment That Pays," a funding proposal developed by the Neighborhood Open Space Coalition to demonstrate that short-term fiscal investment in parks and open spaces will yield long-term financial, ecological, and sociological benefits.
    - Urban Outdoors, 1995-1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 28)
      Urban Outdoors is the electronic newsletter of the Neighborhood Open Space Coalition and Friends of Gateway National Recreation Area.
    - Vegetative Cover and Land Use Classification, 1985 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 29)
    - Waterfront Gateway Trips, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 30)
    - Why Community Gardens Need Insurance, 1995 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 31)
    - Youth Proposal, 1992-1996 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 32)
  - Subseries IV.C. Environmental Policy Forum (EPF), 1976-2002
    The bulk of Subseries IV.C. contains correspondence, minutes, newsletters, and financial documentation for the Environmental Policy Forum (EPF). Formerly known as the New York City Citizens Advisory Committee on Environmental Policy (NYC CAC/EP), the Environmental Policy Forum began in the 1970s as the official advisory committee to New York City's planning for wastewater and coastal management. It evolved into an independent organization committed to the principle of citizen involvement in public solutions to urban environmental problems. Flatow served as Vice President and Vice-Chair for Coastal Management.
    - CAC Reimbursement, 1986-1990 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 26)
    - Choking City, 1990 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 27)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee, 1979-1984 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 28)
    - Citizens Union (3 Folders), 1976-1988 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 29-31)
    - Coastal Bight Meeting, 1984 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 1)
    - Environment and the City Charter Meeting, 1989 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 2)
    - EPF Bank (5 Folders), 1987-2000 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 3-7)
    - EPF Newsletters, 1986-1989 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 8)
    - Forum Invitations, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 9)
    - Gov Board Meetings on Sledge Dumping, 1984 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 10)
    - Jamaica Bay, 1984-2002 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 11)
    - Mailing Lists, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 12)
    - Meeting on SEQRA, 1985 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 13)
    - Meetings (3 Folders), 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 14-16)
    - Minutes & Misc, 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 17)
    - Oil Spill, 1990 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 18)
    - Sign-in Sheets, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 19)
    - Watch on Waterfront Meeting Summaries, 1984 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 20)
    - Waterfront Development, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 21)
    - Environmental Policy Forum Corporate Seal, circa 1980s-1990s (Offsite-box 39)
  - Subseries IV.D. Coalition for the Bight, 1977-2010 (bulk 1970s-1990s)
    The Coalition for the Bight was a public/private partnership created to stimulate a regional constituency to develop consensus on a management plan for the use and restoration of the Bight, better the approach to resolving problems affecting the Bight, and improve the use of scientific information in policy decision-making. The records in Subseries IV.D. include correspondence, project plans, essays, symposium proceedings, proposals, and newsletters that echo these goals and represent the work Eugenia Flatow performed as coordinator of this organization, much of which involved project planning and research.
    - 197-A, 1978-1999, bulk 1991 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1)
      Materials related to "The New Waterfront Revitalization Program: A Proposed 197-A Plan." The City Charter, in Section 197-a, authorizes community boards and borough boards, along with the Mayor, the City Planning Commission, the Department of City Planning, and any Borough President, to sponsor plans for the development, growth, and improvement of the city, its boroughs, and communities.
    - An Analysis of Federal and State Habitat Protection Programs (3 Folders), circa 1994 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 2-4)
    - Bi-State Seafood Development Conference, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 5)
    - Bight Essays, 1987 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 6)
    - Bight Labels, undated (Offsite-box 28, Folder 7)
    - Bight Symposium (2 Folders), 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 8-9)
    - Buffer the Bay: A Survey of Jamaica Bay's Unprotected Open Shoreline and Uplands, 1987 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 10)
    - Buffer the Bay Revisited, 1992 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 11)
    - Cape May to Montauk: A Coastal Protection Report Card, 2002 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 12)
    - Chronology, 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 13)
    - Clean Ocean & Shore Trust Committee (COAST), 1990-2003 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 14)
    - Coalition for the Bight, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 15)
    - Contracts and Vouchers, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 16)
    - General [disassembled binder], 1986 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 17)
    - Habitat Workshop, circa 1990-1991 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 18)
    - ICONN Project (5 Folders), 1977-1995 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 19-23)
    - An Invitation for a Coalition for the Bight, 1987 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 24)
    - Invitation for a New York and New Jersey Harbor Estuary Inspection, 2010 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 25)
    - Letterhead, undated (Offsite-box 28, Folder 26)
    - New York Academy of Sciences (2 Folders), 1985-1988 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Paerdegat Basin (3 Folders), 1987-1997 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 3-5)
    - Planning Committee Task Force, 1986 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 6)
    - Proceedings, May 1987 Symposium (Offsite-box 29, Folder 7)
    - Proposal for a Coastal Zone Project to Join Land Use and Clean Water Issues, undated (Offsite-box 29, Folder 8)
    - Proposal for Organization for Synthesis of Dredge Forum with HEP, 1993 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 9)
    - Proposals (2 Folders), 1985 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 10-11)
    - Proposed Big Apple or HEP Conservancy, 1995 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 12)
    - Public Involvement Coordination Group (4 Folders), 1983-1991 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 13-16)
      Contains PICG newsletters and meeting minutes of the Steering Committee for the Dredged Material Disposal Management Plan for the Port of New York/New Jersey.
    - Public Trust Doctrine, 1984 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 17)
    - Pure Water Alliance (PWA), 1994-1996 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 18)
    - Seminars [disassembled binder], 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 19)
    - Sheepshead Bay, 1993-1994 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 20)
    - Summary of Meeting with Coalition for the Bight, 1988 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 21)
    - Watch on the Waterfront (3 Folders), 1987-1995 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 22-24)
    - Waterfront Planning Areas and Projects, 1984 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 25)
  - Subseries IV.E. New York-New Jersey Harbor Estuary Program (HEP), 1980-2002
    Subseries IV.E. includes drafts, reports, correspondence, proposals, maps, and minutes for the New York-New Jersey Harbor Estuary Program (HEP). Established by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) in 1987, the goal of the NY/NJ Harbor Estuary Program is to establish and maintain a healthy and productive ecosystem with full beneficial uses. Flatow served as a member of the Management Committee and Co-chair of the Citizens Advisory Committee, which represents the public in all HEP dialogue and debate. This subseries also contains a considerable amount of documentation concerning the Citizens Advisory Committee and the HEP's Habitat Workgroup.
    - Action Plan, Environmental Lifestyle Guide, 1989-1992 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1)
    - An Alternative Strategy for Disposal of Dredged Materials from the Greater New York Harbor Region: A Citizens' Proposal, 1984 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 2)
    - Arthur Kill, 1993-2002 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 3)
    - Cleaning Up Our Coastal Waters: An Unfinished Agenda (conference), 1990 March (Offsite-box 33, Folder 4)
    - Containment Islands, 1984 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 5)
    - Draft Environmental Impact Statement: Disposal of Dredged Material From the Port of New York and New Jersey, 1982 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 6)
    - Draft Environmental Impact Statement: Subaqueous Borrow Pit Demonstration Project, 1984 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 7)
    - Dredged Material Disposal Management Program for the Port of New York and New Jersey, 1980 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 8)
    - Feasibility Study For Use of Dredged Material From NY/NJ Harbor as Sanitary Landfill Cover, 1987, 1994 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 9)
    - Guidelines for Monitoring Low Salt Marsh Restoration Projects, 1999 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 10)